Guide to the Boris Garfinkel Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Boris Garfinkel papers
1921-1992
MS 1714
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
6.8
The papers include correspondence, writings, and research notes, which document Boris Garfinkel's research and publications in astronomy.
Garfinkel, Boris, 1904-
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Boris Garfinkel, 1996, and the estate of Boris Garfinkel, 1999.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Boris Garfinkel was born in Rjev, Russia, on November 18, 1904. He earned a Ph.D. in astronomy from Yale University in 1943. Garfinkel worked, from 1946 to 1967, in the Ballistic Research Laboratories at the Aberdeen Proving Ground in Maryland. He then taught at Yale University as a senior research astronomer specializing in celestial mechanics. In 1983 he was made professor emeritus of astronomy.
Scope and Contents
The papers include correspondence, writings, and research notes, which document Boris Garfinkel's research and publications in astronomy.
Astronomy; Ballistics; Celestial mechanics; Aberdeen Proving Ground (Md.); Garfinkel, Boris, 1904-; Yale University. Department of Astronomy
- Additional Material, Accession 1997-M-059
  - Correspondence
    - 1957-1989, n.d. (Box 1)
    - Aksnes, Kaare (Box 1)
    - American Astronomical Society (Box 1)
    - Applications, scholarships, recommendations (Box 1)
    - Cui-Dou-Xing (Box 1)
    - Danby, ______ (Box 1)
    - Deprint, Andre (Box 1)
    - Heard, William B. (Box 1)
    - Hori, G. (Box 1)
    - Jupp, Alan (Box 1)
    - Rademacher, ______ (Box 1)
    - Szebeheley, Victor (Box 1)
    - Vinti, John (Box 1)
    - Whalen, Charles T. (Box 1)
    - Williams, Carol (Box 1)
    - Meetings and travel (Box 2)
    - Publications (Box 2)
  - Photographs (Box 2)
  - Student notes and papers, 1941-1943 (Box 2)
  - Topical files
    - Aberdeen Proving Ground (Box 3)
    - Brouwer Award (Box 3)
    - Brouwer Prize (Box 3)
    - Cranks (Box 3)
    - International Astronomical Union (Box 3)
    - Personal (Box 3)
    - Promotion case and appeal (Box 3)
    - Standard atmosphere (Box 3)
    - Summer Institute in Dynamical Astronomy (SIDA) (Box 3)
    - Teaching materials [course notes, examinations, student papers from Yale University, Ballistic Institute, University of Delaware] (Box 3)
    - Yale appointments (Box 3)
    - Yale University. Department of Astronomy (Box 3)
  - Writings and research [papers, articles, lectures, and notes on topics such as artificial satellite theory, ideal resonance problem, astronomical refraction, celestial mechanics, Trojan asteroids] (Box 4)
  - Writings and research [papers, articles, lectures, and notes on topics such as artificial satellite theory, ideal resonance problem, astronomical refraction, celestial mechanics, Trojan asteroids] (Box 5)
  - Writings and research [papers, articles, lectures, and notes on topics such as artificial satellite theory, ideal resonance problem, astronomical refraction, celestial mechanics, Trojan asteroids] (Box 6)
  - Unidentified or unsorted [some may be writings of others] (Box 6)
- Additional Material, Accession 1999-M-117
  - Aberdeen Proving Ground [correspondence, notes, reports], 1921, undated (Box 1)
  - Yale University [student notebook and notes], 1940-1944 (Box 1)
  - Writings [including lecture notes] (Box 2)